

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

💌 jean-claude.desrosiers@jclaude.xyz | 🖸 jeanclaude-desrosiers | 🛠 www.jclaude.xyz | 📳 (+1) 438-990-4360 | 😾 DesJC | 🛅 jclaude-des

Profile

Communication Fit to work within a team and with clients; fluent in both english and french

Learning Adept at learning computer science skills and concepts, vert quickly

Hardworking Resolve to produce efficient and applied work

Curiosity Interested in low-level programming, theoretical computer science, quantum computing, etc.

Skills_

Programming Fluency with multiple paradigms (object-oriented, declarative, functional, logical, etc.)

System Knowledgeable in low-level (C et MIPS) and machine (VHDL) programming **Development** Experienced in designing and developing Java desktop applications with Maven

Web Knowledgeable in front-end (Bootstrap, Javascript) and back-end (NodeJS, PHP, .NET) development

Mobile Practical experience developing Android and React.js applications for mobile

Database Efficient in SQL query writing and database design

Linux Knowledgeable at using a Linux operating system and command-line utilities

Education

UdeM (Université de Montréal)

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Montreal, Quebec Sept. 2019 - May 2022

Practical and theoretical problems related to software design and development

Awarded two scholarships of excellence in the computer science department in 2020 and 2022

Dawson College Montreal, Quebec

DIPLOMA OF COLLEGIAL STUDIES IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2016 - May. 2019

· Rapid Application Development for desktop, web and mobile environments according to industry standards

Work Experience _____

IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

VOLUNTEER

DesjardinsMontreal, Quebec

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER May 2021 - May 2022

- · Maintenance, exploitation and development with applications such as uCMDB, UD, SmartTrack and BigFix in Python and Java
- Use Windows batch scripting to automate jobs and Python for development
- Apply ITSM processes in the ITIL v.4 framework

Desjardins Montreal, Quebec

Provide technical support for those working in Desjardins caisses

• Work in a team, along other teams, towards a common goal

Bacon Financial Technologies (Hardbacon)

Longueuil, Quebec

Sept. 2019 - April 2021

May 2020 - May 2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Apr. 2019 - May 2019

- · Develop and designing (with a team) a mobile application in React for portfolio management and financial counseling
- Meet deadlines for releases of versions matching the marketing campaign

Extracurricular Activity

Code Club Canada St-Philippe, Quebec

Develop a series of activities for kids to playfully learn how to code with Scratch and Microbit

- Build an introductory class on web technologies (HTML/CSS/JS) for adolescents
- · Animate said activities, weekly, in a small group